# **Alexis Bellot**

# Machine Learning Research Scientist

### **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

My research spans algorithms, theory, and applications of machine learning and causal inference.

I am interested in better understanding how to guarantee valid and robust predictions in the context of heterogeneous data from multiple different environments, for applications in reinforcement learning, treatment effect estimation, and the safety of AI algorithms.

**EMPLOYMENT HISTORY** 

### **Research Scientist**

Google DeepMind

May 2022 - Present, London, UK.

- Research on causality and its applications.
- Visiting Researcher, Imperial College London (May 2023 May 2024).

### **Postdoctoral Research Scientist**

Columbia University

June 2021 - May 2022, New York, USA.

- Topic: Causal inference.
- Advisor: Prof. Elias Bareinboim.

**EDUCATION** 

## Ph.D. Applied Mathematics

University of Cambridge / Alan Turing Institute Sept. 2017 – May 2021, Cambridge, UK.

- Thesis title: Hypothesis Testing and Causal Inference with Heterogeneous Medical Data.
- Advisor: Prof. Mihaela van der Schaar.

# M.Sc. Applied Statistics

University of Oxford

Sept. 2016 - Sept. 2017, Oxford, UK.

- Grade: Distinction.
- Courses in Graphical Models, Applied Statistics, Foundations of Statistical Inference, Bayes Methods, Computational Statistics.

### **B.Sc.** Mathematics

Imperial College London

Sept. 2013 - June. 2016, London, UK.

- Grade: First Class Honours.
- Foundational courses in all areas of Mathematics with a specialization in Statistics.

Last updated Jul. 24th 2024

alexis.b11@hotmail.com

Social github personal website linkedin

google scholar

Languages

Spanish (native)
French (native)
Luxembourgish (native)

English (native)

German (conversational)

### Workshop organization

- AAAI 2023 Bridge Program on Continual Causality Co-organizer
- NeurIPS 2022 workshop "A Causal View on Dynamical Systems" Co-organizer
- NeurIPS 2021 Workshop "Causal Inference & Machine Learning: Why now?" (WHY-21) Member of logistics committee

### Courses

Imperial College London – Course on Foundations of Causal Inference and Modern Topics – 2023

#### **Seminars**

- MSc Health Data Analytics and Machine Learning, Imperial College London An Introduction to Causal Discovery 2024
- The Mathematics of Machine Learning, Imperial College London An Introduction to Causality 2023
- Msc Mathematical Finance, Imperial College London An Introduction to Transportability 2022
- CCAIM summer school, Cambridge University Lecture on Transfer Learning and Causality 2022
- DataSig, Imperial College London Causal discovery in dynamical systems 2022
- Rice ECE Speaker Series Seminar, Rice University Policy Analysis using Synthetic Controls in Continuous-time 2022
- Inspiration exchange, Cambridge University MIRACLE: Missing data imputation using causal insights 2021
- Ellis Health Foundation Accounting for unobserved confounding in domain generalization 2019
- Microsoft Research Conditional Independence Testing using Generative Adversarial Networks 2019
- GlaxoSmithKline Conditional Independence Testing using Generative Adversarial Networks 2018

### **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. K. Jalaldoust\*, A Bellot\*, E. Bareinboim, "Partial Transportability for Domain Generalization", Tech report, 2024.
- 2. J. Schrouff, et al., "Mind the Graph When Balancing Data for Fairness or Robustness", arxiv, 2024.
- 3. V. Aglietti, et al., "FunBO: Discovering Acquisition Functions for Bayesian Optimization with FunSearch", arxiv, 2024.
- 4. A. Bellot, "Towards Bounding Causal Effects under Markov Equivalence", UAI, 2024.
- 5. **A. Bellot**, M. van der Schaar, "Scoring DAGs with Dense Unobserved Confounding", IEEE Transactions on Neural Networks and Learning Systems, 2024
- 6. **A. Bellot**, J. Zhang, E. Bareinboim, "Scores for Learning Discrete Causal Graphs with Unobserved Confounders", AAAI, 2024.
- 7. A. Bellot, A. Malek, S. Chiappa, "Tranportability for Bandits with Data from Multiple Environments", NeurIPS, 2023.
- 8. L. Gultchin, V. Aglietti, A. Bellot, S Chiappa, "Functional Causal Bayesian Optimization", UAI, 2023.
- 9. **A Bellot\***, A Dhir\*, G Prando, "Generalization Bounds and Algorithms for Estimating Conditional Average Treatment Effect of Dosage", arxiv, 2022.
- 10. N. Seedat, F. Imrie, A. Bellot, Z. Qian, M. van der Schaar "Continuous-time modeling of counterfactual outcomes using neural controlled differential equations", ICML, 2022.
- 11. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Consistency of mechanistic causality in continuous-time using Neural ODEs", ICLR, 2022.
- 12. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Accounting for Unobserved Confounding in Domain Generalization", arxiv, 2022.
- 13. T. Kyono, Y. Zhang, A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "MIRACLE: Causal Structure Learning and Exploitation for Imputing Missing Data", NeurIPS, 2021.
- 14. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Policy Analysis using Synthetic Controls in Continuous-time", ICML, 2021.
- 15. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Application of Kernel Hypothesis Testing on Set-valued Data", UAI, 2021.
- 16. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "A Kernel Two-Sample Test with Selection Bias", UAI, 2021.
- 17. **A. Bellot**, R. A. Floto, M. van der Schaar, "Al-based Hypothesis Testing in Individuals with CF", Pediatric Pulmonology (Abstract), 2020.

- 18. Y. Zhang, **A. Bellot**, M. van der Schaar, "Learning Overlapping Representations for the Estimation of Individualized Treatment Effects", AISTATS, 2020.
- 19. Z. Qian, A. Alaa, **A. Bellot**, M. van der Schaar, "Learning Dynamic and Personalized Comorbidity Networks from Event Data using Deep Diffusion Processes", AISTATS, 2020.
- 20. T. Cowling, D. Cromwell, A. Bellot, and others. "Logistic regression and machine learning predicted patient mortality from large sets of diagnosis codes comparably", Journal of Clinical Epidemiology, 2020
- 21. T. Cowling, **A. Bellot**, and others. "One-year mortality of colorectal cancer patients: development and validation of a prediction model using linked national electronic data", British Journal of Cancer, 2020.
- 22. Y. Ruan, **A. Bellot**, and others. "Predicting the Risk of Inpatient Hypoglycemia With Machine Learning Using Electronic Health Records", Diabetes Care, 2020.
- 23. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "A Bayesian Approach to Modelling Longitudinal data", ACM Computing for Healthcare, 2020.
- 24. **A. Bellot**, M. van der Schaar, "Conditional Independence Testing using Generative Adversarial Networks", NeurIPS, 2019.
- 25. **A. Bellot**, M. van der Schaar, "Boosting Transfer Learning with Survival Data from Heterogenous Domains", AISTATS, 2019
- 26. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Multitask Boosting for Survival Analysis with Competing Risks", NeurIPS, 2018.
- 27. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Boosted Trees for Risk Prognosis", Machine Learning for Healthcare Conference, 2018.
- 28. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "Tree-based Bayesian Mixture Model for Competing Risks", AISTATS, 2018.
- 29. A. Bellot, M. van der Schaar, "A Hierarchical Bayesian Model for Personalized Survival Predictions", IEEE J. BHI, 2018.